Rachel, let me see.
瑞秋，给我看
- Can I see? - Finders keepers. And I found it.
- 借我看看 - 谁找到就是谁的，这是我找到的
Did you have dream?
你又在做梦吗？
Nightmare.
可怕的恶梦
Worse than this place?
比这地方更可怕？
- Again? - Until they kill you.
- 又要干架？ - 不打死你绝不罢休
Can they kill me before breakfast?
那就在吃早餐前打死我吧
You are in hell, little man.
臭小子，你活在地狱
And I am the devil.
而我就是魔王
Solitary.
关到禁闭室
- Why? - For protection.
- 为什麽？ - 为了保护
- I don't need protection. - Protection for them.
- 我才不需要保护 - 保护他们不被你打死
Get in.
进去
Are you so desperate to fight criminals...
你这麽想打击罪犯…
...that you lock yourself in to take them on one at a time?
不惜入狱和他们单挑？
Actually, there were seven of them.
其实我一共有七个对手
I counted six, Mr. Wayne.
我只算到有六个，韦恩先生
How do you know my name?
你怎麽知道我的名字？
The world is too small for someone like Bruce Wayne to disappear...
布鲁斯韦恩仍是个大人物
...no matter how deep he chooses to sink.
不管你有多麽落魄潦倒
Who are you?
你是谁？
My name is merely Ducard, but I speak for Ra's al Ghul...
敝姓杜卡 我是忍者大师的代言人
...a man greatly feared by the criminal underworld.
他是犯罪集团的克星
A man who can offer you a path.
他可以指引你一条明路
What makes you think I need a path?
你凭什麽认为我需要指引？
Someone like you is only here by choice.
你这种人是自愿来这种地方
You have been exploring the criminal fraternity...
你想深入了解罪犯的世界
...but whatever your original intentions...
不管你的目的是什麽
...you have become truly lost.
你已经迷失了方向
And what path can Ra's al Ghul offer?
忍者大师能指引我走哪条路？
The path of a man who shares his hatred of evil...
你和他一样痛恨邪恶力量
...and wishes to serve true justice.
你也希望能伸张正义
The path of the League of Shadows.
也就是影武者联盟之路
- You're vigilantes. - No, no, no.
- 你们是以暴制暴的私刑者 - 并不是
A vigilante is just a man lost in the scramble for his own gratification.
在你争我夺之中失利的人 才会变成以暴制暴的私刑者
He can be destroyed or locked up.
他们会被击毁或遭囚禁
...if you devote yourself to an ideal...
为一个崇高理想全心投入
...and if they can't stop you...
他们就无法阻止你
...then you become something else entirely.
你也将成为另一种人
Which is?
什麽人？
Legend, Mr. Wayne.
传奇英雄，韦恩先生
Tomorrow, you will be released.
明天你将被释放
If you are bored of brawling with thieves and want to achieve something...
如果你想打击更凶狠的罪犯
...there is a rare blue flower that grows on the eastern slopes.
东边的山坡有一种罕见的蓝花
Pick one of these flowers.
摘下一朵蓝花
If you can carry it to the top of the mountain...
如果你能把它带到山巅
...you may find what you were looking for in the first place.
也许就能找到你当初在寻找的东西
And what was I looking for?
我在寻找什麽？
Only you can know that.
只有你自己知道
You turn back. You go back.
回去，你一定要回头
Ra's al Ghul?
忍者大师？
Wait.
且慢
What are you seeking?
你在寻找什麽？
I seek...
我在寻找…
...the means to fight injustice.
打击犯罪、伸张正义的方法
To turn fear...
让制造恐惧的恶徒…
...against those who prey on the fearful.
心生恐惧
To manipulate the fears in others...
你要让别人心生恐惧
...you must first master your own.
就必须先战胜自己内心的恐惧
Are you ready to begin?
你准备开战了吗？
I can... I can barely stand.
我连站都站不起来
Death does not wait for you to be ready!
死神不会等你准备好
Death is not considerate or fair!
死神绝不手下留情！
And make no mistake, here you face death.
你面对死神吧，不容有失
Tiger.
虎爪
Jujitsu.
柔术
Panther.
豹掌
You're skilled. But this is not a dance.
身手不错，但这不是儿戏
And you are afraid.
而且你仍然害怕
But not of me.
但不是怕我
Tell us, Mr. Wayne...
告诉我，韦恩先生
...what do you fear?
你害怕什麽？
Bruce?
布鲁斯？
It's okay. It's okay.
没事了，没事了
You'll be okay.
你不会有事的
Will we be needing an ambulance, Master Wayne?
老爷，我要叫救护车吗？
No, I'll set the bone and take him for an x-ray later.
我先替他接骨，待会再照Ｘ光
Very good, sir.
好的，老爷
- I'm very sorry, sir. I've told... - Don't worry. It's fine.
- 对不起，老爷 - 别担心，他没事
Took quite a fall, didn't we, Master Bruce?
你跌得很惨，对吧，少爷？
And why do we fall, Bruce?
我们为什麽跌倒，布鲁斯？
So we can learn to pick ourselves up.
这样才能学会站起来
Just a little fall. It's just a small fracture.
只是小跌了一下，轻微骨折而已
The bats again?
你又想到那些蝙蝠？
You know why they attacked you, don't you?
你知道们为什麽攻击你吗？
- They were afraid of you. - Afraid of me?
- 因为们怕你 - 们怕我？
All creatures feel fear.
每种生物都有恐惧
Even the scary ones?
就连可怕的怪物也有？
Especially the scary ones.
尤其是可怕的怪物
I got something to show you.
我给你看样东西
- You think your mother will like them? - Yeah.
- 你想你妈会喜欢吗？ - 当然会
- I think it's time to get up. - Maybe.
- 你该起床了吧？ - 好啦
No going back to bed.
不准赖床
Did you build this train, Dad?
爸，高架铁路是你盖的吗？
Gotham's been good to our family, but the city's been suffering.
高谭市对韦恩家族很好 但这城市日渐没落
People less fortunate than us have been enduring very hard times.
小老百姓的日子过得很辛苦
So we built a new, cheap, public transportation system to unite the city.
於是我们建造经济的大众交通工具 把全体市民连结在一起
And at the center...
正中央就是…
...Wayne Tower.
韦恩大楼
- Is that where you work? - No, I work at the hospital.
- 你在那里上班吗？ - 不，我在医院工作
I leave the running of our company to much better men.
我把公司交给更好的人管理
- Better? - Well...
- 比你更好的人？ - 嗯…
...more interested men.
比我对做生意更有兴趣的人
Can we go?
我们可以走吗？
Please.
拜托
Okay. Let's go.
好，我们走吧
- What's wrong, Bruce? - No, no. It was me.
- 布鲁斯，你怎麽了？ - 不是他，是我
I just needed some fresh air.
是我想要出来透透气
A little bit of opera goes a long way. Right, Bruce?
歌剧听久了很累人，对吧？
Come on. Let's go.
我们回家吧
Wallets, jewelry. Come on, fast.
皮夹和珠宝，快点
- That's fine. - Fast.
- 没问题 - 快点
Take it easy.
别紧张
Here you go.
拿去吧
It's fine. It's fine.
没关系，没关系
Now just take it and go.
把皮夹拿去，放过我们
- I said, jewelry. - Hey...
- 我要那串珍珠项链 - 喂…
Thomas!
汤玛斯！
Bruce.
布鲁斯
It's okay.
没关系
Don't be afraid.
不要害怕
Is this your father's?
那是你父亲的大衣吗？
It's okay.
没关系
Come here.
过来
There you go.
穿好了
It's okay.
没事了
Gordon.
戈登
Hey.
嘿
Good news.
好消息
We got him, son.
我们逮到凶手了
You're in excellent hands.
你什麽都不用操心
We'll be watching the empire.
我们会好好打理公司
When you grow up, it'll be waiting for you.
等你长大了再让你接管
I thought I might prepare a little supper.
我替你准备了晚餐
- Very well. - Alfred?
- 好吧 - 阿福？
- Yes, Master Bruce? - It was my fault, Alfred.
- 是，布鲁斯少爷 - 都是我的错
- I made them leave the theater. - No.
- 我叫他们离开的 - 不是
- lf I hadn't gotten scared... - It was nothing that you did.
- 要是我不害怕… - 这不是你的错
It was him, and him alone.
是凶手一个人的错
Do you understand?
明白吗？
I miss them, Alfred. I miss them so much.
我想念他们，我好想念他们
So do I, Master Bruce.
我也是，布鲁斯少爷
So do I.
我也是
And do you still feel responsible for your parents' death?
你还是认为是你害死你父母的吗？
My anger outweighs my guilt.
我的愤怒比罪恶感更多
Come.
来吧
You have learned to bury your guilt with anger.
你学会了用愤怒代替罪恶感
I will teach you to confront it and to face the truth.
我会教你接受它并面对事实
You know how to fight six men. We can teach you how to engage 600.
你可以一个人对付六个人 我要教你一个人对付六百人
You know how to disappear.
你知道怎麽把自己藏起来 我可以教你怎麽隐形
Invisible?
隐形？
The ninja understands that invisibility is a matter of patience and agility.
忍者的隐形术全是靠耐心 和矫捷的身手
Always mind your surroundings.
耳听四面、眼观八方
Ninjitsu employs explosive powders.
忍者会运用火药
- As weapons? - Or distractions.
- 做为武器？ - 或是障眼法
Theatricality and deception are powerful agents.
戏剧效果和障眼法很有效
You must become more than just a man in the mind of your opponent.
你不能让敌人把你当成凡人
- Who is he? - He was a farmer.
- 他是谁？ - 一个农夫
Then he tried to take his neighbor's land and became a murderer.
他为了抢邻居的农地杀人
- Now he is a prisoner. - What'll happen to him?
- 现在变成一名囚犯 - 他会有什麽下场？
Justice. Crime cannot be tolerated.
杀人就要偿命，不能姑息养奸
Criminals thrive on the indulgence of society's understanding.
社会漠不关心才会让治安败坏
Your parents' death was not your fault.
你父母的死不是你的错
It was your father's.
是你父亲的错
Anger does not change the fact that your father failed to act.
你不能改变他不敢反击的事实
- The man had a gun. - Would that stop you?
- 对方的手上有枪 - 那能阻止你吗？
I've had training.
我接受过武术训练
The training is nothing!
那不是重点
Will is everything!
决心才重要
The will to act.
主动出击的决心
Yield.
投降吧
You haven't beaten me.
你并没有打败我
You have sacrificed sure footing for a killing stroke.
你为了杀敌失去重心
Rub your chest.
用力磨擦胸口
Your arms will take care of themselves.
你的手可以帮你取暖
You are stronger than your father.
你比你父亲更坚强
You didn't know my father.
你不了解我父亲
But I know the rage that drives you.
我了解你内心的愤怒
That impossible anger strangling the grief...
你的愤怒让你暂时忘却伤痛 直到你无法承受
...poison in your veins.
对亲人的思念
And one day, you catch yourself wishing the person you loved had never existed...
有一天你会希望他们不存在
...so you'd be spared your pain.
好让你的痛苦消失
I wasn't always here in the mountains.
我并不是一直都住在山上
Once, I had a wife.
我也有过一个妻子
My great love.
我一生的最爱
She was taken from me.
她惨遭杀害
Like you, I was forced to learn there are those without decency...
我和你一样学会不能纵容坏人
...who must be fought without hesitation, without pity.
对他们绝对不能手下留情
Your anger gives you great power.
愤怒给了你很大的力量
But if you let it, it will destroy you...
但若不学会控制，它会毁了你
...as it almost did me.
愤怒差点毁了我一生
- What stopped it? - Vengeance.
- 你是如何平息怒气？ - 报仇
That's no help to me.
这对我没有用
Why, Bruce?
为什麽？
Why could you not avenge your parents?
你为什麽不为父母报仇？
Will you be heading back to Princeton after the hearing, sir...
听证会後你要回普林斯顿大学
...or can I persuade you to stay on for a day or two?
还是你愿意多留一、两天？
I'm not heading back at all.
我不要回去
- You don't like it there? - I like it fine.
- 你不喜欢那里？ - 我很喜欢
They just don't feel the same way.
只是校方不喜欢我
- I've prepared the master bedroom. - No.
- 我安排你睡在主卧室 - 不用
My room will be fine.
我睡我的房间就行
With all due respect, sir, Wayne Manor is your house.
恕我直言，韦恩宅邸是你的
No, Alfred, it's my father's house.
不，这是我父亲的
- Your father is dead. - This place is a mausoleum.
- 你父亲过世了，少爷 - 这地方是他的陵墓
If I have my way, I'll pull the damn thing down brick by brick.
我宁愿把它的一砖一瓦拆掉
This house, Master Wayne, has sheltered six generations of your family.
这是韦恩家族世代相传的宅邸
Why do you give a damn, Alfred? It's not your family.
你干嘛在乎？ 这又不是你家
I give a damn because a good man once made me responsible...
我之所以在乎是因为一位好人…
...for what was most precious to him...
把他心爱的独子
...in the whole world.
托付给我
Miss Dawes has offered to drive you to the hearing.
道斯小姐要载你到法院
She probably hopes to talk you out of going.
她大概想劝你不要去
Should I just bury the past out there with my parents, Alfred?
我应该把过去也埋在地下吗？
I wouldn't presume to tell you what to do with your past, sir.
我不能告诉你该如何面对过去
Just know that there are those of us who care about what you do with your future.
但是有很多人关心你的未来
Haven't given up on me yet?
你还没放弃我，是吗？
Never.
永远都不会
Alfred still keeps the condensed milk on the top shelf.
阿福一向都把炼奶放在最上面
Hasn't he noticed you're tall enough to reach now?
- 他不知道你已长高、拿得到了吗？ - 我猜那是老习惯吧
- Never used to stop us anyway. - No, it didn't.
- 我们小时候一样有办法拿到 - 没错
How's your mom?
你母亲好吗？
She misses this place.
她很怀念这地方
So do I.
我也一样
Yeah.
是啊
But it's nothing without the people who made it what it was.
只可惜现在已经人事全非了
- Now there's only Alfred. - And you.
- 只有阿福还在这里 - 还有你呀
- I'm not staying, Rachel. - You're just back for the hearing.
- 我不会留下来，瑞秋 - 你只是回来参加听证会
Bruce, I don't suppose there's any way to convince you not to come.
我知道谁也无法阻止你去
Someone at this proceeding...
这场听证会总得有人…
...should stand for my parents.
代表我父母出席
We all loved your parents, Bruce.
我们都很爱你的父母
- What Chill did is unforgivable. - Then why is your boss letting him go?
- 凶手齐利的行为不可原谅 - 但是你的上司却要让他出狱
In prison, he shared a cell with Carmine Falcone.
他和卡曼费康尼是牢友
He learned things, and he will testify in exchange for early parole.
他愿意出庭作证交换提前假释
Rachel, this man killed my parents.
瑞秋，他杀死我父母
I cannot let that pass.
我不能忘记这件事
And I need you to understand that, please.
我希望你能了解我的心情
Okay.
好吧
The depression hit working people, like Mr. Chill, hardest of all.
经济大萧条害齐利先生走投无路
His crime was appalling, yes, but it was motivated not by greed...
虽然他的罪行令人发指 但他是走投无路才铤而走险
Given the 14 years served, as well as his extraordinary level of cooperation...
他已服刑１４年，并将协助我们
...we strongly endorse his petition for early release.
因此我们要求让他假释出狱
Mr. Chill?
齐利先生？
Your Honor...
法官大人
...not a day goes by that I don't wish I could take back what I did.
我每天都为我做的事深感悔恨
Sure, I was desperate, like a lot of people back then...
我当时的确是走投无路
...but that don't change what I did.
但这不能改变我的所作所为
I gather there is a member of the Wayne family here today.
今天有一位韦恩家族成员在场
Has he got anything to say?
他有话要说吗？
- He's coming out the side! - He's coming out the side, guys!
- 他从侧门出来了 - 他从侧门出来了，各位！
Joe! Hey, Joe!
乔，乔！
Falcone says hi.
费康尼老大向你问好
Come on, Bruce. We don't need to see this.
走吧，布鲁斯
I do.
我要看
The DA couldn't understand why Judge Faden...
法官坚持要举行公开听证会
Falcone paid him off to get Chill out in the open.
他一定是被费康尼老大收买了 让齐利公开露面
Maybe I should thank them.
也许我应该感谢他们才对
- You don't mean that. - What if I do, Rachel?
- 你不是说真的 - 也许我是说真的，瑞秋
My parents deserved justice.
是该为我父母伸张正义
You're not talking about justice. You're talking about revenge.
这不是伸张正义而是报仇雪恨
- Sometimes, they're the same. - No, they're never the same.
- 有时候这两者是一样的 - 不，绝对不一样
Justice is about harmony. Revenge is about you making yourself feel better.
伸张正义是为了维持社会和谐 报仇只是为了逞一时之快
- It's why we have an impartial system. - Your system is broken.
- 所以才会有公正的司法制度 - 司法制度早已名存实亡
You care about justice? Look beyond your own pain, Bruce.
你想伸张正义就要忘却伤痛
This city is rotting.
这个城市已经沉沦腐败
They talk about the depression as if it's history. It's not.
他们说经济大萧条已成历史，才怪
Things are worse than ever here.
老百姓的日子越来越苦
Falcone floods our streets with crime and drugs...
黑帮老大费康尼趁火打劫、无恶不作
...preying on the desperate, creating new Joe Chills every day.
逼人走上不归路，满街都是齐利之辈
Falcone may not have killed your parents, Bruce...
他也许没有亲手杀死你父母
...but he's destroying everything that they stood for.
却毁了他们代表的一切
You wanna thank him for that? Here you go.
你想感谢他就去吧
We all know where to find him. As long as he keeps the bad people rich...
大家都知道他在哪里
Good people like your parents, who'll stand against injustice, they're gone.
你父母这种仗义执言的好人 找不到了
What chance does Gotham have when the good people do nothing?
没人挺身而出，高谭市就完了
- I'm not one of your good people, Rachel. - What do you mean?
- 我不是你说的好人 - 什麽意思？
All these years, I wanted to kill him.
这些年来我一直想杀他 现在没机会了
Your father would be ashamed of you.
你父亲会以你为耻
You're taller than you look in the tabloids, Mr. Wayne.
你本人看来比报上的照片高大
No gun? I'm insulted.
你没带枪？ 真瞧不起人
- You could've just sent a thank-you note. - I didn't come here to thank you.
- 你大可以寄张感谢卡给我就好 - 我不是来感谢你的
I came to show you that not everyone in Gotham's afraid of you.
我要告诉你并不是人人都怕你
Only those who know me, kid.
认识我的人才怕我
Look around you. You'll see two councilmen...
你自己看，这里有两位市议员
...a union official, couple off-duty cops...
一位工会代表，两名警察
...and a judge.
和一位法官
I wouldn't have a second's hesitation of blowing your head off in front of them.
我大可以在他们面前毙了你
Now, that's power you can't buy.
这种权力是买不到的
That's the power of fear.
这就是恐惧的力量
I'm not afraid of you.
我并不怕你
Because you think you got nothing to lose.
你自以为能完全豁出去
But you haven't thought it through.
但是你没有想清楚
You haven't thought about your lady friend in the DA's office.
你没想到在地检署工作 青梅竹马的女朋友
your old butler.
还有对你忠心耿耿的老管家
People from your world...
像你这种人
...have so much to lose.
有太多牵挂了
Now, you think because your mommy and your daddy got shot...
你以为你爹娘被人一枪打死
...you know about the ugly side of life, but you don't.
就能了解人性的丑陋吗？
You've never tasted desperate.
你根本就不知道民间疾苦
You're... You're Bruce Wayne, the prince of Gotham.
你是高谭市的天之骄子
You'd have to go 1000 miles to meet someone who didn't know your name.
你的大名无人不知、无人不晓
So don't come here with your anger, trying to prove something to yourself.
别正气凛然地跑来当一个大英雄
This is a world you'll never understand.
你完全不了解犯罪世界
And you always fear...
你不了解的事
...what you don't understand.
永远会让你害怕
All right.
动手吧
Yeah, you got spirit, kid. I'll give you that.
我倒是很佩服你的胆识
More than your old man anyway.
你比你老子更带种
In the joint, Chill told me about the night he killed your parents.
齐利在牢里跟我提到你父母
He said your father begged for mercy.
他说你老爸向他…
Begged.
跪地求饶
Like a dog.
像条狗一样哀号
Should've tipped better.
你一定是小费给太少了
- For what? - Your jacket.
- 你要什麽？ - 你的外套
Okay.
好吧
Hey, hey, hey. Let me have it. It's a nice coat.
给我吧，这件大衣不错
Be careful who sees you with that.
别被人看到你穿这件大衣
- They're gonna come looking for me. - Who?
- 他们会来找我 - 谁？
Everyone.
每个人
It's...
这件…
It's a nice coat.
这件大衣真不错
When you lived among the criminals, did you start to pity them?
当你和坏人同流合污，会同情他们吗？
The first time I stole so that I wouldn 't starve, yes.
会的，当我第一次为了吃饭偷东西时
I lost many assumptions about the simple nature of right and wrong.
我突然失去了是非善恶的观念
And when I traveled...
当我到处闯荡
...I learned the fear before a crime...
我到犯罪前的恐惧
...and the thrill of success.
以及得手後的兴奋
But I never became one of them.
但是我从来没变成坏人
Fool. What do I care what your name is? You're a criminal.
我管你叫什麽，你只是个犯人
Tell that to the guy who owned these.
你去和这批货的主人说吧
You've traveled the world to understand the criminal mind and conquer your fears.
你为了克服内心恐惧 并洞悉犯罪心理而走遍全世界
But a criminal is not complicated.
但是罪犯的内心并不复杂
And what you really fear is inside yourself.
你真正害怕的是自己的内心
You fear your own power.
你害怕你自己的力量
You fear your anger...
你也害怕你内心的愤怒…
...the drive to do great or terrible things.
会逼你做出伟大或可怕的事
Now you must journey inwards.
你必须克服你的内心恐惧
You are ready.
准备好了
Breathe.
吸气
Breathe in your fears.
把你的恐惧吸进去
Face them.
面对你的恐惧
To conquer fear, you must become fear.
你要成为恐惧本身，才能克服它
You must bask in the fear of other men.
你必须造成别人的恐惧
And men fear most what they cannot see.
而大家都害怕看不见的东西
You have to become a terrible thought.
你必须让人想到你就害怕
A wraith.
成为死神化身
You have to become an idea!
让坏人闻风丧胆
Feel terror cloud your senses.
感受恐惧如何模糊你的感官
Feel its power to distort.
让恐惧的力量扭曲你的身心
To control.
掌控你的一切
And know that this power can be yours.
这股恐惧的力量才会属於你
Embrace your worst fear.
拥抱你最深层的恐惧
Become one with the darkness.
和恐惧的黑暗力量融为一体
Focus.
全神贯注
Concentrate.
全心投入
Master your senses.
随心所欲控制你的全身
You cannot leave any sign.
你不能露出你的行踪
I haven't.
我并没有
Impressive.
很好
We have purged your fear.
我们已经消除你的恐惧
You are ready to lead these men.
你可以当这批勇士的首领
You are ready to become a member of the League of Shadows.
你可以加入影武者联盟
But first, you must demonstrate your commitment to justice.
但首先要证明你矢志维护正义
No.
不
I'm no executioner.
我不是刽子手
Your compassion is a weakness your enemies will not share.
敌人不会对你手下留情
That's why it's so important.
这才是重点
It separates us from them.
这就是我们和他们的不同
You want to fight criminals. This man is a murderer.
你想打击犯罪，他就是杀人犯
- This man should be tried. - By whom?
- 他应该接受审判 - 受谁审判？
Corrupt bureaucrats?
让贪污腐败的法官来审判？
Criminals mock society's laws.
坏人根本没把法律放在眼里
You know this better than most.
你比任何人都清楚这一点
You cannot lead these men...
你不能率领他们
...unless you are prepared to do what is necessary to defeat evil.
除非你能不择手段打击犯罪
And where would I be leading these men?
我要率领他们到哪里？
Gotham.
高谭市
As Gotham's favored son...
你是高谭市的天之骄子
...you will be ideally placed to strike at the heart of criminality.
你有能力瓦解高谭市的恶势力
- How? - Gotham's time has come.
- 我该怎麽做？ - 高谭市的气数已尽
Like Constantinople or Rome before it...
就跟君士坦丁堡和古罗马一样
...the city has become a breeding ground for suffering and injustice.
高谭市已经沦为万恶的城市
It is beyond saving and must be allowed to die.
它无可救药，必须将它毁灭
This is the most important function of the League of Shadows.
这是影武者联盟最重要的任务
It is one we've performed for centuries.
也是我们数百年来的使命
Gotham...
高谭市…
...must be destroyed.
一定要被摧毁
You can't believe in this.
你不会信这种鬼话吧？
Ra's al Ghul rescued us from the darkest corners of our own hearts.
忍者大师将我们从 内心最黑暗的角落拯救出来
What he asks in return is the courage to do what is necessary.
他要求我们以勇气 行当行之事回报他
I will go back to Gotham and I will fight men like this...
我会回高谭市对付这类坏人
...but I will not become an executioner.
但是我不会当刽子手
Bruce, please.
布鲁斯，别这样
For your own sake, there is no turning back.
你要想清楚，你已不能回头
- What are you doing? - What's necessary, my friend.
- 你是在干什麽？ - 行我当行之事
I will tell him you saved his life.
我会跟他说你救他一命
Master Wayne, you've been gone a long time.
韦恩少爷，你消失好一阵子
- Yes, I have. - You look very fashionable.
- 是啊 - 你这身打扮很时髦
Apart from the mud.
只是有点脏
Are you coming back to Gotham for long, sir?
你这次会待很久吗？
As long as it takes.
需要待多久就待多久
I want to show the people...
我要让高谭市市民知道
...their city doesn't belong to the criminals and the corrupt.
这城市不属於贪官与罪犯
In the depression, your father nearly bankrupted Wayne Enterprises...
经济大萧条期间你爸为了消弭贫穷
...combating poverty.
几乎倾家荡产
He believed his example could inspire the wealthy of Gotham to save their city.
他相信他能让有钱人共襄盛举 拯救高谭市
Did it?
他成功了吗？
In a way.
算是吧
Their murder shocked the wealthy and the powerful into action.
他惨遭谋杀，为有钱有势的人敲响警钟
People need dramatic examples to shake them out of apathy.
人们的漠不关心 唯有戏剧性大逆转才能唤醒
I can't do that as Bruce Wayne.
身为布鲁斯韦恩做不了什麽
As a man...
我只是个血肉之躯
...I'm flesh and blood, I can be ignored, destroyed.
很容易被忽视、摧毁
But as a symbol...
但是成为正义化身
As a symbol, I can be incorruptible.
我就永远不会被击败
- I can be everlasting. - What symbol?
- 永远正气长存 - 什麽化身？
Something elemental...
一种原始的…
...something terrifying.
可怕的化身
I assume that as you take on the underworld...
你单枪匹马对抗犯罪集团
...this symbol is a persona to protect those you care about from reprisals?
我以为这化身是会 保护你关心的人不被报复
You're thinking about Rachel?
你说的是瑞秋吗？
Actually, sir, I was thinking of myself.
其实我说的是我自己
Have you told anyone I'm coming back?
有人知道我回来吗？
I couldn't figure the legal ramifications of bringing you back from the dead.
我不敢让人知道你死而复生
- Dead? - You've been gone seven years.
- 死而复生？ - 你失踪了七年
You had me declared dead?
你对外宣布我死了？
Actually, it was Mr. Earle. He's taking the company public.
其实是厄尔先生，他要让公司上市
He wanted to liquidate your majority shareholding.
他也要把你的股票卖掉
Those shares are worth quite a bit of money.
那些股票值很多钱
Well, it's a good thing I left everything to you, then.
幸好我把全部财产都留给你
Quite so, sir.
是的，少爷
And you can borrow the Rolls, if you like. Just bring it back with a full tank.
我的劳斯莱斯可以借你开 回来时别忘了加满油
In my opinion, Mr. Zsaz is as much a danger to himself as to others...
我认为萨兹先生会试图自杀并危害他人
...and prison is probably not the best environment for his rehabilitation.
因此监狱并不适合他
- Dr. Crane. - Miss Dawes.
- 克莱恩医师 - 道斯小姐
You think a man who butchers people for the mob doesn't belong in jail?
你真的认为黑道杀手不该坐牢？
I would hardly have testified to that otherwise, would I?
我若不这麽认为，就不会替他辩护
This is the third of Falcone's thugs you've had declared insane...
费康尼老大有三个杀手
...and moved into your asylum.
被你送进精神疗养院
The work offered by organized crime must have an attraction to the insane.
混黑道一定很容易被逼疯
Or the corrupt.
或是被收买
Mr. Finch.
芬奇先生
You should check with Miss Dawes here...
你最好劝劝道斯小姐
...just what implications your office has authorized her to make. If any.
不要无凭无据对我提出指控
- What are you doing? - What are you doing, Carl?
- 瑞秋，你这是在做什麽？ - 你又是在做什麽，卡尔？
Looking out for you.
我是在保护你
Falcone has half the city bought and paid for.
费康尼收买了一半的政府官员
- Drop it. - How can you say that?
- 放弃吧 - 你怎麽能这麽说？
Because as much as I care about getting Falcone, I care more about you.
我痛恨费康尼，但我更关心你
That's sweet.
我知道你对我好
We've been through all that.
但我不能接受
Blessed bat again, sir.
又有一只蝙蝠飞进来
They nest somewhere in the grounds.
们的巢穴一定在地底
No more favors. Someone is sniffing around.
我不帮你了，有人对我起疑心
Hey, I scratch your back, you scratch mine, doc.
我帮你，你帮我
I'm bringing in the shipments.
我替你们把货运进来
We are paying you for that.
我们有付你钱
Maybe money isn't as interesting to me as favors.
付钱并不算是帮我的忙
I am more than aware that you are not intimidated by me, Mr. Falcone.
我知道你并不怕我，费康尼先生
But you know who I'm working for, and when he gets here...
但是等我的老板来了以後…
He... He's coming to Gotham?
他要来高谭市？
Yes, he is.
是的
And when he gets here, he's not going to wanna hear...
他来了以後会想听到…
...that you've endangered our operation just to get your thugs out of jail time.
你为了几个小混混危害我们的行动
- Who's bothering you? - There's a girl at the DA's office.
- 谁在找你麻烦？ - 地检署的一个女孩
- We'll buy her off. - Not this one.
- 我们用钱收买她 - 她不要钱
Idealist, huh?
原来是理想主义者
Well, there's an answer to that too.
我也有办法对付这种人
- I don't want to know. - Yes, you do.
- 我并不想知道 - 你非知道不可
No, we are showing very healthy growth in these sectors.
其它部门的业绩有稳健的成长
I don't think Thomas Wayne would have viewed heavy-arms manufacture...
汤玛斯韦恩绝对不会同意…
...as a suitable cornerstone for our business.
让公司变成军火制造商
Well, that's 20 years ago, Fredericks.
那是二十年前的事，佛德瑞
I think after 20 years we can allow ourselves...
汤玛斯韦恩都死了二十年
...to stop thinking about what Thomas Wayne would have done.
我们不必再管他怎麽想
Good morning, Mr. Earle's office.
早安，厄尔先生办公室
Yes, he's confirmed for the dinner tomorrow evening.
是的，他确定明天会出席晚宴
Good morning. I'm here to see Mr. Earle.
早安，我来见厄尔先生
Name?
请问贵姓大名？
Bruce Wayne.
布鲁斯韦恩
Thomas would probably not have taken the company public.
汤玛斯也许不会让公司上市
But that is what we, as responsible managers, are going to do.
但我们为了公司一定要这麽做
Jessica?
洁西卡？
Jessica? Where are you?
洁西卡？ 你在哪里？
- Eye on the ball, and... - Why is no one answering the phone?
- 盯着小白球看… - 你为什麽不接电话？
It's Wayne Enterprises, Mr. Earle. I'm sure they'll call back.
放心，对方一定会再打来
Bruce? You're supposed to be dead.
布鲁斯？ 你不是死了吗？
I'm sorry to disappoint.
抱歉让你失望了
- I need you to take a look at this. - Have you seen him yet?
- 你要看看这份文件 - 你见到他了吗？
- Who? - Wayne.
- 谁？ - 韦恩
It's been all over the news. He's back.
新闻整天都在播，他回来了
I'm sure you realize I can't stop the big machine.
请你了解这件事势在必行
Too many wheels turning.
时势如此
- We're going public. - I understand.
- 公司一定要上市 - 我了解
And I'll be handsomely rewarded for my shares.
我也会分到不少钱
I'm not looking to interfere.
我并不想干涉公司行政
- I am looking for a job. - Oh?
- 我只想要一份工作 - 哦？
I just want to get to know the company that my family built.
我想多了解我的家族企业
Any ideas where you would start?
你想先进哪个部门？
Applied Sciences caught my eye.
我对应用科技部门有兴趣
Fox's department.
福克斯的部门
I'll let him know you're coming.
我会通知他
You look like him. Your dad.
你跟你爸长得很像
You're the only one left of the Wayne family.
你是韦恩家族唯一的遗孤
This is where you belong. Welcome home.
这是你的家，欢迎回家
Environmental procedures, defense projects, consumer products.
环保科技、军火、消费产品
All prototypes. None in production.
全都是实验原型 并没有进入量产阶段
- On any level whatsoever. - None?
- 完全没有 - 完全没有？
What did they tell you this place was?
他们是怎麽跟你说这部门的？
They didn't tell me anything.
他们什麽都没说
Earle told me exactly what it was when he sent me down here.
厄尔倒是跟我说得很明白
Dead end.
我被打入冷宫
Place to keep me from causing the board any more trouble.
好让我不在董事会上找麻烦
Come on.
来吧
- You were on the board? - When your father ran things.
- 你曾经是公司董事？ - 当你父亲还在的时候
- You knew my father? - Oh, yeah.
- 你认识我父亲？ - 是啊
Helped him build his train.
我协助他建造高架铁路系统
Here we are.
到了
Kevlar utility harness.
多功能强化防护带
Gas-powered, magnetic grapple gun.
汽动式磁力钩爪枪
The 350-pound test monofilament.
承受重量高达１５８公斤
Wonderful project, your dad's train.
你爸设计的铁路系统很棒
Routed it right into Wayne Tower, along with the water and power utilities.
每一条路线都直达韦恩大楼 水电管线也直接连到这里
Kind of made Wayne Tower the unofficial center of Gotham City.
让韦恩大楼成为高谭市的命脉
Of course, Earle let it go to rot. Here we are.
厄尔却让它荒废，请看
Nomex survival suit for advanced infantry.
先锋部队的装甲衣
Kevlar biweave, reinforced joints.
克维拉纤维，强化护肘护膝
- Tear-resistant? - This sucker will stop a knife.
- 防裂材质？ - 连刀都刺不穿
- Bulletproof? - Anything but a straight shot.
- 防弹吗？ - 刀枪不入
- Why didn't they put it into production? - Bean counters didn't think...
为什麽不量产？
So, what's your interest in it, Mr. Wayne?
你为什麽对这些感兴趣？
I want to borrow it.
我想借来用
For spelunking.
我要做洞穴探险
Spelunking?
洞穴探险？
Yeah, you know, cave diving?
对，到山洞探险
You expecting to run into much gunfire in these caves?
有人会在山洞向你开枪吗？
Look, I'd rather Mr. Earle didn't know about me borrowing...
我不希望让厄尔知道…
Mr. Wayne...
韦恩先生
...the way I see it...
对我来说
...all this stuff is yours anyway.
这一切都是你的
Okay. Give it a try.
好了，试试看
Charming.
真是个好地方
At least you'll have company.
至少你有很多同伴
This must be the lowest foundation of the southeast wing.
这一定是东南厢房的地基
Your great-great-grandfather was involved in the Underground Railroad...
你曾祖父在内战时透过地下管道
...secretly transporting freed slaves to the North...
秘密将黑奴运送来北方
...and I suspect these caverns came in handy.
我怀疑就是偷藏在这些洞穴
Alfred! Come up here!
阿福，过来看看
I can see everything all right from down here, sir, thank you.
我在这里就看得见，多谢了
We order the main part of this cowl from Singapore.
头罩的主要零件来自新加坡
Via a dummy corporation.
透过傀儡公司进口
Indeed. And then, quite separately...
是的
...we place an order to a Chinese company for these.
这零件则是向中国公司订购
- Put it together ourselves. - Precisely.
- 然後我们自己组装 - 没错
They'll have to be large orders, to avoid suspicion.
大量订购才不会让人起疑
- How large? - Say 10,000.
- 有多少？ - 一万个
- Well, at least we'll have spares. - Yes.
- 至少会有很多备用品 - 是啊
Don't suppose you want a taste.
你不分一杯羹吗？
I just keep offering, thinking maybe someday you'll get wise.
我在想也许有一天你会学聪明
There's nothing wise in what you do, Flass.
你这麽做一点都不聪明
Well, Jimbo, you don't take the taste, makes us guys nervous.
老詹，你不收贿让大家很紧张
I'm no rat.
我不会告密
In a town this bent, who's there to rat to anyway?
大家都被收买，我能向谁告状？
Don't turn around.
别转身
You're a good cop. One of the few.
你是硕果仅存的好警察
What do you want?
你要干什麽？
Carmine Falcone brings in shipments of drugs every week.
费康尼每星期都进一批毒品
Nobody takes him down. Why?
为什麽没人阻止他？
He's paid up with the right people.
他收买了警察和法官
What will it take to bring him down?
该怎麽做才能制止他？
Leverage on Judge Faden...
向斐登法官施压
...and a DA brave enough to prosecute.
找一个有胆识的检察官
Rachel Dawes.
瑞秋道斯
Who are you?
你是谁？
Watch for my sign.
注意我的信号
You're just one man?
你只有一个人？
Now we're two.
现在我们有两个人
We?
我们？
Freeze!
站住！
What the hell was that?
那是什麽人？
Just some nut.
只是一个疯子
Well, what is it today? More spelunking?
今天你又要去洞穴探险吗？
No. Today it's BASE-jumping.
不，今天我要定点跳伞
BASE-jumping.
定点跳伞？
- That like parachuting? - Kind of.
- 像是高空跳伞吗？ - 差不多
Do you have any lightweight fabrics?
你有轻质布料吗？
You know, I think I have just the thing.
我正好有你要的布料
It's called memory cloth. Notice anything?
这叫记忆布料，看到吗？
Regularly flexible...
和一般布料一样轻柔
...but put a current through it...
但是一旦通上电流
...molecules realign, it becomes rigid. - What kind of shapes can you make?
- 分子重新组合後就会变硬 - 你可以做成什麽形状？？
Can be tailored to fit any structure based on a rigid skeleton.
只要有骨架，什麽形状都行
Too expensive for the Army?
军方又嫌太贵吗？
I don't think they tried to market it to the billionaire, BASE-jumping crowd.
他们没想到亿万富翁会有兴趣 去洞穴探险或定点跳伞
- Look, Mr. Fox. - Yes, sir?
- 福克斯先生 - 是的
If you're uncomfortable...
如果你觉得不妥…
Mr. Wayne, if you don't want to tell me exactly what you're doing...
只要你不跟我实话实说
...when I'm asked, I don't have to lie.
我被问到就不必说谎
But don't think of me as an idiot.
不过别以为我是傻子
Fair enough.
好吧
What's that?
那是什麽？
The Tumbler?
那辆弹力车？
Oh, you wouldn't be interested in that.
你不会有兴趣的
She was built as a bridging vehicle.
这是造桥用的越野车
During combat, two of these would jump over a river, towing cables.
作战时可以拉着缆绳跳过河流
Over here on the throttle, flip that open and throttle up.
只要让推进器全速前进
This will boost you into a rampless jump... Not now!
它就能越过任何障碍 不要乱来！
Not... Not now, sir.
小子，别乱来
Afterburner disengaged.
关闭再燃装置
We never could get the damn bridge to work...
我们一直没办法造桥
...but this baby works just fine.
不过这辆车性能超强
So, what do you think?
你觉得怎样？
Does it come in black?
有黑色车款吗？
I need you at the docks Thursday.
我要你星期四到码头
- Problems? - I don't want any trouble...
- 有麻烦吗？ - 最後一批货…
...with the last shipment. - Sure.
- 最後一批货不能出错 - 好吧
Word on the street is you got a beef with somebody in the DA's office.
听说有一位检察官在找你麻烦
- Is that right? - And that there's a fat prize...
- 是吗？ - 听说你肯付…
...waiting for anybody willing to do anything about it.
一大笔钱把她除掉
So, what's your point, Mr. Flass?
你想说什麽，佛莱斯警官？
Have you seen the girl?
你看过那女孩吗？
It's a cute little assistant D A.
她是个美女助理检察官
Don 't you think that's a little too much heat to bring down, maybe?
拿她开刀不太好吧？
- Even for this town. - Never underestimate Gotham City.
- 你会激起众怒 - 别太高估高谭市的治安
People get mugged coming home from work every day of the week.
每天都有人下班被抢
Sometimes... Sometimes things just go bad.
有时候就是会莫名其妙走霉运
It's a problem with the graphite, sir.
这批货的石墨含量太高
The next 10,000 will be up to specifications.
下一批货一定没问题
- At least they gave us a discount. - Quite.
- 至少厂商给我们打了折 - 是啊
In the meantime, sir, may I suggest you try to avoid landing on your head?
我建议你最好暂时不要撞到头
Why bats, Master Wayne?
你为什麽选择蝙蝠？
Bats frighten me.
蝙蝠让我感到恐惧
It's time my enemies shared my dread.
我也要让敌人一样畏惧我
What is this?
这是干嘛？
Continue.
继续干活吧
Looks fine out there.
看起来没问题
The bears go straight to the dealers.
玩具熊直接交给毒贩吗？
Yeah, and the rabbits go to the man in the Narrows.
对，玩具兔要运到奈何岛
- What's the difference? - Ignorance is bliss, my friend.
- 这两种毒品有什麽不同？ - 你最好不要知道
Don't burden yourself with the secrets of scary people.
你惹不起那些大魔头
Hey. Steiss.
小史？
What?
干嘛？
What the...?
搞什麽？
I better check it.
我最好去看看
There's a problem out here. You better bail.
大事不妙，你最好闪人
Where are you?!
你在哪里？
Here.
这里
Get going. Oh, shit.
快开车，哦，要命！
What the hell are you?
你是什麽东西？
I'm Batman.
我是蝙蝠侠
Nice coat.
好帅的大衣
Thanks.
谢了
Hold it.
别过来
That's right, you better run.
给我滚远一点
Falcone sent them to kill you.
费康尼派他们来杀你
- Why? - You rattled his cage.
- 为什麽？ - 你把他惹毛了
- What's this? - Leverage.
- 这是什麽？ - 你的筹码
- For what? - To get things moving.
- 用来做什麽？ - 把坏人绳之以法
Who are you?
你是谁？
Someone like you.
像你一样
Someone who'll rattle the cages.
想要伸张正义的人
Ma'am? Everything okay?
小姐，你没事吧？
- Falcone's men? - Does it matter?
- 他们是费康尼的手下？ - 逮到他们也没用
We'll never tie him to it anyway.
费康尼一样有办法脱身
I wouldn't be too sure of that.
这次他脱不了身
What the hell is that?
这是怎麽回事？
Cut him down.
把他放下来
Unacceptable.
这不可原谅
Now, I don't care if it's rival gangs, Guardian Angels...
我不管他是帮派死对头、守护天使
...or the goddamn Salvation Army...
或是什麽救世主
...get them off the street and off the front page.
把他抓起来，别让他出风头
They say it was just one guy. Or a creature.
听说他是一个人，或是一个怪物
It was some asshole in a costume.
他只是奇装异服的怪胎
- Yeah? - This guy did deliver us...
- 干嘛？ - 他抓到…
...one of the city's biggest crime lords.
势力最大的黑帮老大
No one takes the law into their own hands in my city.
没人能在我的辖区动私刑
Understand?
明白吗？
- No way to bury it now. - There's still Judge Faden.
- 他这次难逃法律制裁 - 斐登法官会罩他
- I've got Faden covered. - What about this bat they babble about?
- 我能对付斐登法官 - 大家都说是一只蝙蝠干的？
Even if these guys will swear to being thrashed by a giant bat...
就算他们作证说是大蝙蝠干的
...we've got Falcone at the scene.
费康尼还是被逮个正着
Drugs, prints, cargo manifests. This bat character gave us everything.
蝙蝠侠把他犯案的证据都给我
Okay. Let's do it.
那就起诉他吧
- Bats are nocturnal. - Bats may be.
- 蝙蝠是夜行动物 - 也许是吧
But even for billionaire playboys, 3:00 is pushing it.
不过你也不能睡到下午三点
The price for leading a double life, I fear.
这是过双重生活的代价
Your theatrics made an impression.
你制造的戏剧效果很唬人
Theatricality and deception...
戏剧效果和障眼法…
...are powerful weapons, Alfred. This is a good start.
能打击犯罪 这是好的开始
If those are to be the first of many injuries to come...
如果你以後会一直受伤
...it would be wise to find a suitable excuse.
就要找很好的藉口
Polo, for instance.
比如说打马球
I'm not learning polo, Alfred.
我又不会打马球
Strange injuries, a nonexistent social life.
无缘无故受伤，缺乏社交生活
These things beg the question...
大家一定会怀疑
...as to what exactly does Bruce Wayne do with his time and his money.
布鲁斯韦恩大少爷都在搞什麽鬼
What does someone like me do?
像我这种人都做什麽？
Drive sports cars, date movie stars.
开名贵跑车，泡漂亮女星
Buy things that are not for sale.
买一些别人买不起的东西
Who knows, Master Wayne, you start pretending to have fun...
韦恩少爷，当你假装找乐子
...you might even have a little by accident.
也许真的会找到快乐
Sir.
老板
- We have a situation. - All right.
- 出了状况 - 什麽事？
The Coast Guard picked up one of our cargo ships last night...
海巡队昨晚发现我们的货轮
...heavily damaged, all crew missing, probably dead.
船身受损，船员失踪 大概全都丧命
The ship was carrying a prototype weapon.
货轮载了一具微波发射器
It's designed for desert warfare, but it...
是用来进行沙漠战争的
It looks like somebody...
但是看起来有人…
...turned it on.
利用它杀人
It uses focused microwaves to vaporize the enemy's water supply.
它能发射微波蒸发敌人的供水
The damage to the ship was catastrophic.
货轮严重受损
The weapon itself is...
那具武器也…
Missing?
不见了？
Yeah.
对
Mr. Wayne.
韦恩先生
Nice car.
这辆车好酷
You should see my other one.
我的另一辆车更酷
He's done something the police never have.
他逮到警方抓不到的大坏蛋
You can't take the law into your own hands.
他不能动用私刑
Well, at least he's getting something done.
至少他在打击犯罪
Bruce, help me out here.
布鲁斯，你来评评理
Well, a guy who dresses up like a bat clearly has issues.
一个扮成蝙蝠的人一定有毛病
But he's put Falcone behind bars.
可是他把费康尼关起来
And now the cops want him. What does that tell you?
警方并不领情，那代表什麽？
They're jealous.
那代表他们嫉妒他
Sir, the pool is for decoration...
水池是装饰用的
...and your friends do not have swimwear.
不能下去游泳
Well, they're European.
她们是欧洲豪放女
I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
我要请你们离开
- It is not a question of money. - Well, you see...
你给我再多小费也没用
...I'm buying this hotel...
我要买下这家饭店
...and setting some new rules about the pool area.
新规定，从今以後水池可以游泳
I think the Batman deserves a medal.
我觉得应该颁奖给蝙蝠侠
And a straitjacket to pin it on.
把他送进疯人院才对
Thank you.
谢谢
Bruce?
布鲁斯？
Rachel?
瑞秋？
I'd heard you were back.
我听说你回来了
What are you doing?
你在干嘛？
Just swimming here. Wow, it is good to see you.
只是泡泡水，见到你真好
You were gone a long time.
你离开了好久
- I know. How are things? - The same.
- 是啊，你好吗？ - 老样子
Job's getting worse.
工作越来越辛苦
Can't change the world on your own.
光靠自己是不能改变世界的
What choice do I have...
我没有别的选择
...when you're too busy swimming?
你只会忙着和辣妹泡水
Rachel, all of...
瑞秋，这…
All this...
这一切
It's... It's not me. It's...
不是真正的我
Inside, I am...
其实我的内心…
I am more.
并没有这麽肤浅
Come on, Bruce. Come on.
快来嘛，布鲁斯
Bruce, we have some more hotels for you to buy.
咱们再去多买几家饭店
Bruce...
布鲁斯
...deep down you may still be that same great kid you used to be.
你内心深处仍是那个正直的小孩
But it's not who you are underneath...
但是在你外表底下是谁并不重要
...it's what you do that defines you.
你的所作所为才重要
Dr. Crane, thanks for coming.
克莱恩医师，谢谢你来访
Not at all. He cut his wrists?
不客气，他想割腕自杀？
Probably looking for the insanity plea. But if anything should happen...
他想装疯脱罪，不过万一出事…
Of course, better safe than sorry.
还是保险一点比较好
Yeah, Dr. Crane, I can't take it anymore. It's all too much.
我受不了了，我快发疯了
The walls are closing in. Blah, blah, blah.
我一定要出去
A couple of days of this food, it'll be true.
再吃几天牢饭我真的会发疯
- What do you want? - I wanna know...
- 你要什麽？ - 我要知道…
...how you're gonna convince me to keep my mouth shut.
你打算怎麽让我闭嘴
About what? You don't know anything.
你什麽都不知道
I know you don't want the cops to take a closer look at the drugs they seized.
我知道你怕警方仔细查那批毒品
And I know about your experiments with the inmates of your nut house.
也知道你替囚犯进行人体实验
See, I don't go into business with a guy without finding out his dirty secrets.
我一定会先查出合夥人的底细
And those goons you used.
你找来的打手
I own the muscle in this town.
都是我的人
Now, I've been bringing your stuff in for months...
我一直替你把货运进来
...so whatever he's planning, it's big, and I want in.
你的老板一定想大干一票 要算我一份
Well, I already know what he'll say.
我知道他会怎麽说
That we should kill you.
我们应该杀了你灭口
Even he can't get me in here. Not in my town.
他在我的地盘动不了我
Would you like to see my mask?
你想看我的面具吗？
I use it in my experiments.
我用它来做实验
Now, I'm probably not very frightening to a guy like you.
你这大恶人不会觉得可怕
But these crazies, they can't stand it.
不过疯子就会被吓死
So when did the nut take over the nut house?
原来疯人院是你这疯子开的
They scream and they cry...
他们都跟你一样
...much as you're doing now.
大哭大叫
Well, he's not faking. Not that one.
他这次并不是装疯
I'll talk to the judge and see if I can get him moved...
我会和法官谈谈 把他送到我的精神病院
...to the secure wing at Arkham. I can't treat him here.
他待在这儿没有救
Storm's coming.
一场大风暴即将来临
The scum is getting jumpy because you stood up to Falcone.
你逮到费康尼让黑道很紧张
It's a start. Your partner was at the docks with Falcone.
你的搭档和费康尼挂勾
Well, he moonlights as a low-level enforcer.
他有时候也帮黑道办事
They were splitting the shipment in two. Only half went to the dealers.
毒品分成两半，一半交给毒贩
Why? What about the other half?
那另一半呢？
- Flass knows. - He won't talk.
- 佛莱斯知道 - 他不会说
He'll talk to me.
他一定会跟我说
Commissioner Loeb set up a massive task force to catch you.
罗柏局长成立专案小组追捕你
- He thinks you're dangerous. - What do you think?
- 他认为你是危险人物 - 你认为呢？
I think you're trying to help.
我认为你想尽力帮忙
But I've been wrong before.
不过有时候我会看错人
Come on, I ain't got all night.
快点，别慢吞吞
Flass, I have kids to feed.
拜托，我有小孩要养
What, they don't like falafel?
他们不爱吃三明治吗？
Where were the other drugs going?
另一批毒品在哪里？
I never knew. I don't know.
我不知道
- I swear to God. - Swear to me!
- 我对天发誓 - 对我发誓
I don't... I don't know. I never knew. Never.
我一直都不知道
They went to some guy for a couple days before they went to the dealers.
那批毒品先送去给另一个人
Why?
为什麽？
There was something... Something else in the drugs...
他在毒品里加了其它的料
...something hidden. - What?
- 不知名的料 - 什麽料？
I never went to the drop-off point. It was in the Narrows.
我只知道那批货被送到奈何岛
- Cops only go there in force. - Do I look like a cop?
- 警察只有成群结队武装起来才敢去 - 我像是警察吗？
No...
不！
This is the one I'm talking about.
就是这箱货柜
- What's your problem with it? - It shouldn't exist.
- 有问题吗？ - 它不该存在的
This ship left Singapore with 246 containers, but arrived with 247.
从新加坡出发时只有２４６箱 现在却有２４７箱
I'm guessing there's something I'm not supposed to find in there.
这里面一定有违禁品
Listen, counselor, we don't wanna know what's in Mr. Falcone's crate.
我们不敢查费康尼老大的货柜
Things are working a little differently now. Open it up.
现在情况不同了，快打开来
What the hell is this?
这到底是什麽？
It's you, isn't it? Everybody's been talking about you.
就是你，大家都在说你
Get in here!
快进来！
The other kids won't believe me.
别的小朋友一定不相信的
Get rid of all traces.
湮灭所有证据
- Better torch the whole place. - All right.
- 放火把这地方烧掉 - 好吧
Having trouble?
你不舒服吗？
Take a seat. Have a drink.
坐下来，喝口水
You look like a man who takes himself too seriously.
你看起来火气很大
Do you want my opinion? You need to lighten up.
我觉得你应该降降火气
Alfred, help me.
阿福？ 阿福？
Blood. Take. Take poison. Blood poison.
我中了毒…替我验血
Poisonous. Poisonous.
中毒，中毒了
Bruce...
布鲁斯
...why do we fall?
布鲁斯，我们为什麽跌倒？
- How long was I out? - Two days.
- 我昏迷了多久？ - 两天
It's your birthday.
今天是你生日
Many happy returns.
祝你生日幸福快乐
I've felt these effects before, but this was so much more potent.
我有过这种经验，这次更强烈
It was some kind of hallucinogen, weaponized, in aerosol form.
这是一种迷幻药 被做成喷剂当作武器
You have been hanging out in the wrong clubs, Mr. Wayne.
你一定是在夜店被人下了药
I called Mr. Fox when your condition worsened after the first day.
是我把福克斯先生请来
I analyzed your blood...
我替你验血，把接受体合成物 和蛋白质催化素分离出来
Am I meant to understand any of that?
你能不能说白话？
Not at all. I just wanted you to know how hard it was.
可以，我费了好一番功夫
- Bottom line, I synthesized an antidote. - Could you make more?
- 终於制造出一种抗体 - 你可以制造更多吗？
You planning on gassing yourself again, Mr. Wayne?
你打算再吸毒吗？
Well, you know how it is. You're out at night, looking for kicks...
你也知道，泡夜店狂欢
...someone's passing around the weaponized hallucinogens...
总是有被下迷幻药的风险
I'll bring what I have. The antidote should inoculate you for now.
我把手上有的给你 注射抗体後就不怕被下药
Alfred, always a pleasure.
阿福，很高兴见到你
Lucius.
卢修
- You sure you don't want to come in? - I have to get back.
- 你真的不进来吗？ - 我得赶回去，请你转交给他
- I wanted to leave this. - Thank you.
谢谢你
Rachel?
瑞秋？
Looks like someone's been burning the candle at both ends.
看来有人在蜡烛两头烧
- Must've been quite an occasion. - It is my birthday.
- 你昨晚一定玩得很疯 - 今天是我生日
I know. I'm sorry I can't come tonight. I was just dropping off your present.
我知道，今晚我不能来 我只是来送礼物
- You've got better plans? - My boss has been missing for days...
- 你有别的事要忙吗？ - 我的上司失踪了两天
...which means I should probably start by looking at the bottom of the river.
这代表我要开始找他的铺
- Rachel. - Excuse me.
- 瑞秋 - 对不起
Rachel Dawes.
瑞秋道斯
Who authorized that? Get Crane down there now. Don't take no for an answer.
是谁下的命令？ 无论如何都要把克莱恩找来
Call Dr. Lehmann, tell him we need our own assessment to the judge by morning.
请李曼医师明天一早交出报告
- What's wrong? - It's Falcone.
- 怎麽了？ - 费康尼出事了
Dr. Crane moved him to Arkham Asylum on suicide watch.
克莱恩把费康尼送到精神病院
You're going to Arkham now? It's in the Narrows, Rachel.
亚克汉疗养院在奈何岛， 你现在要去？
You enjoy your party, Bruce.
你去狂欢吧，布鲁斯
- Some of us have work to do. - You be careful.
- 我得去工作 - 你千万要小心
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
But, Master Wayne, the guests will be arriving.
少爷，客人就快来了
Keep them happy until I arrive.
趁我回来之前
Tell them that joke you know.
说笑话给他们听
Having fun?
玩得开心吗？
Bill? Now, what's a big shot like you doing in a place like this?
比尔？ 你这大人物怎麽会跑来这里？
I need some information.
我要一些资料
The Wayne Enterprise 47-B, 1 -ME.
韦恩企业４７Ｂ、１ＭＥ型产品
1 -ME.
１ＭＥ型
It's a microwave emitter. It was designed to vaporize an enemy's water supply.
能够蒸发敌人供水的微波发射器
Rumor was they tested dispersing water-based chemicals into the air...
听说被实验用来在空中散播化学物
...but isn't that illegal?
这不是不合法吗？
I want all the information on the development of this project...
我要这项实验的所有资料
...all data, files, backup disks, on my desk right away.
立刻把备份档案和文件送来
Did you lose one?
你弄丢了吗？
I'm merging your department with Archives.
我要把这部门和档案部合并
And I am firing you.
我也要开除你
Didn't you get the memo?
你没收到通知吗？
Scarecrow.
稻草人
Miss Dawes, this is most irregular.
道斯小姐，你不必来这里
I have nothing to add to the report I filed with the judge.
我把报告都交给法官了
- I have questions about your report. - Such as?
- 你的报告有疑点 - 什麽疑点？
Isn't it convenient for a 52-year-old man who has no history of mental illness...
一个没有精神病史的５２岁中年人
...to have a psychotic breakdown just when he's about to be indicted?
怎麽会在起诉前突然完全精神崩溃？
As you can see for yourself, there is nothing convenient about his symptoms.
你也看到他的病情有多严重
- Scarecrow. - What's "scarecrow"?
- 稻草人 - 稻草人是什麽？
Patients suffering delusional episodes often focus their paranoia...
产生幻觉的精神病患
...on an external tormentor...
都会幻想被外在力量迫害
...usually one conforming to Jungian archetypes.
通常是某种可怕人物
In this case, a scarecrow.
他的幻觉是稻草人
- He's drugged? - Psychopharmacology is my primary field.
- 他服了药？ - 我专攻精神病药物学
I'm a strong advocate.
我强烈支持用药物控制精神疾病
Outside, he was a giant.
他在外面呼风唤雨
In here, only the mind can grant you power.
在这里只能乖乖听话
You enjoy the reversal.
你很得意，对吧？
I respect the mind's power over the body.
我认为精神胜於肉体
It's why I do what I do.
所以我专门治疗精神病患
I do what I do to keep thugs like Falcone behind bars, not in therapy.
但我专门把坏人关进牢里 不是住在疯人院
I want my own psychiatric consultant to have full access to Falcone...
我要另外请医师为他进行诊断
...including blood work. Find out what exactly you put him on.
包括验血 查出你到底给他吃什麽药
- First thing tomorrow, then. - Tonight.
- 请他明天一早再来 - 他今晚就会来
I've already paged Dr. Lehmann at County General.
我已经通知了李曼医师
As you wish.
随你便
This way, please.
这里请
There's something I think you should see.
我要给你看样东西
This is where we make the medicine.
这里是我们的药厂
Perhaps you should have some, clear your head.
你也该吃一点药，让头脑清醒
Who knows you're here?
谁知道你来这里？
Who knows?
谁知道？
He's here.
他在这里
Who?
谁？
The Batman.
蝙蝠侠
- What do we do? - What anyone does...
- 我们该怎麽办？ - 有坏人闯进来…
...when a prowler comes around.
该怎麽办？
- Call the police. - You want the cops here?
- 报警呀 - 你要把警察找来？
At this point, they can't stop us.
警察拿我们没办法
But the Batman has a talent for disruption.
但是蝙蝠侠会坏事
Force him outside, the police will take him down. Go.
把他逼出去，让警察毙了他
- What about her? - She hasn't got long.
- 那她怎麽办？ - 她没救了
I gave her a concentrated dose.
我下的药很强 她撑不住的，快去吧
The things they say about him.
听说他很神？
Can he really fly?
他真的会飞吗？
I heard he can disappear.
我听说他能隐形
Well, we'll find out.
我们很快就会知道
Won't we?
不是吗？
Taste of your own medicine, doctor?
这下你要自食其果了
What have you been doing here?
你在这里搞什麽鬼？
Who are you working for?
你替谁工作？
Ra's... Ra's al Ghul.
忍者…忍者大师
Ra's al Ghul is dead. Who are you working for?
忍者大师死了，你替谁工作？
Crane.
克莱恩？
Dr. Crane isn't here right now.
克莱恩医师不在
But if you'd like to make an appointment...
如果你想预约挂号…
Batman, put down your weapons and surrender.
蝙蝠侠，放下武器投降
You're surrounded.
你被包围了
- What are you waiting for? - Backup.
- 你还在等什麽？ - 支援警力
- Backup? - The Batman's in there.
- 支援警力？ - 蝙蝠侠在里面
SWAT's on the way. But if you wanna go in now...
霹雳小组正赶来，如果你想冲进去…
...I'll be right behind you, sir.
我们会跟着你
SWAT's on the way.
等霹雳小组来了再说
- Hey.
- 喂
What's happened to her?
她怎麽了？
Crane poisoned her with a psychotropic hallucinogen, a panic-inducing toxin.
她被克莱恩下了迷幻药 引发严重的恐慌症
- Let me get her down to the medics. - They can't help her, but I can.
- 我把她送到医院 - 没有用，我能救她
Get her downstairs. Meet me in the alley.
把她抱下去，在小巷等我
Crane's been smuggling his toxin hidden in Falcone's drugs...
费康尼也被克莱恩下了药
...and they're dumping it into the water supply.
他也在高谭市的自来水管下药
- What was he planning? - I don't know.
- 他想干什麽？ - 我不知道
Was he working for Falcone?
他替费康尼工作吗？
He mentioned someone else, someone worse.
他提到另一个更可怕的人
She needs the antidote before the damage is permanent.
我得赶快为她注射抗体
- How long does she have? - Not long.
- 她还有多久时间？ - 不久
What is that?
那是什麽声音？
- Backup. - What the...?
- 支援来了 - 搞什麽？
Excuse me.
抱歉
- How is she? - She's fading. We gotta go.
- 她怎麽样？ - 她昏过去了，快走吧
I'll get my car.
我去开车
I brought mine.
我开了我的车
Yours?
你的车？
I've gotta get me one of those.
我也要弄一辆这麽炫的车
- He is in a vehicle. - Make and color?
- 他开车逃走 - 车款和颜色？
It's a black...
那是辆黑色的…
...tank.
装甲车
Stay calm.
保持冷静
You've been poisoned.
你中毒了
I'm on him.
我追上去了
Breathe slowly.
慢慢呼吸
Hold on.
撑着点
- What are you doing? - Shortcut.
- 你在干嘛？ - 抄近路
Air One to ground, block that ramp.
挡住他的去路
He's got no way off that roof.
他无处可逃
Turn off your engine. Step away from the car.
马上熄火，乖乖下车
- Trust me. - Weapons system activated.
- 相信我 - 启动武器系统
Who is this guy?
这家伙到底是谁？
- Where's he going? - He's on the roof.
- 他去哪里？ - 他在屋顶
- What street is he taking? - He's not on a street.
- 他走哪一条街？ - 不在街上
He's flying on rooftops.
他在屋顶上开车
At least tell me what it looks like.
他的车到底长什麽样子？
Never mind.
算了
Got him.
追上了
Coming right up on his butt.
我们就跟在他後面
We're tracking suspect vehicle heading west on l- 17.
嫌犯朝往州际公路开去
- Air One to ground. - I lost him.
- 呼叫地面… - 他甩掉我们了
We've lost visual. Exit 9 is blocked.
我们失去他的踪影， 九号出口已封闭
We'll loop back to check the frontage road.
我们去前面查查看
Stealth mode activated.
启动秘密行动模式
Stay with me.
保持清醒
What...? There he is.
他在那里
Just hold on.
撑着点
Rachel!
瑞秋！
- They get any of this into the mains? - Yeah.
- 自来水管被下了毒药吗？ - 没错
Notify the water company. There's gotta be a way to isolate it.
通知自来水厂，一定有办法… 全市的供水系统都被下药
No. They put it all in. They must've been at this for weeks.
他们一定花了几个星期下药
- Gotham's entire water supply is laced. - Why haven't we felt the effects?
已经溶入全市的供水系统了
Must be a compound that has to be absorbed through the lungs.
这种毒药必须从肺部吸入
How do you feel?
你感觉如何？
Where are we?
这是那里？
- Why did you bring me here? - lf I hadn't, your mind would be lost.
- 你为什麽把我带来？ - 我把你救回来，否则你就失常了
- You were poisoned. - It was...
- 你中了毒 - 是…
- It was Dr. Crane. - Rest. Gordon has Crane.
- 是克莱恩下的药 - 好好休息，克莱恩被戈登逮捕了
Is Sergeant Gordon your friend?
戈登警官是你的朋友吗？
I don't have the luxury of friends.
我不能有任何朋友
I'm gonna give you a sedative. You'll wake up back at home.
我给你打镇定剂 你醒来後就会在你家
When you do, get these to Gordon, and Gordon alone. Trust no one.
然後你要把这些交给戈登 千万不要相信别人
- What are they? - The antidote.
- 这是什麽？ - 毒药的抗体
One for Gordon to inoculate himself, the other for mass production.
一瓶给戈登，另一瓶大量制造
Mass production?
大量制造？
Crane was just a pawn. We need to be ready.
克莱恩只是爪牙，我们要准备应战
When you told me your grand plan for saving Gotham...
当你说你想拯救高谭市
...all that stopped me from calling the men in white coats...
我没把你送进疯人院是因为…
...was when you said it wasn't about thrill-seeking.
你说你不是为了追求刺激
- It's not. - What would you call that?
- 我并不是 - 那这算什麽？
- Damn good television. - It's a miracle no one was killed.
- 很精采的新闻 - 没有人受伤是个奇
I didn't have time to observe the rules of the road, Alfred.
我没时间遵守交通规则
You're getting lost inside this monster of yours.
你一手创造了一个怪物
I'm using this monster to help other people, just like my father did.
我利用这个怪物帮助人们 就跟我父亲一样
For Thomas Wayne, helping others...
你父亲那麽做
...wasn't about proving anything to anyone, including himself.
不是为了证明给任何人看， 包括他自己
It's Rachel, Alfred. She was dying.
我是为了瑞秋，她中了毒
She's downstairs, sedated. I need you to take her home.
她就在楼下，请你送她回家
Well, we both care for Rachel, but what you're doing has to be beyond that.
我们都很关心瑞秋 但你已失去控制
It can't be personal, or you're just a vigilante.
为了徇私，就会变成恶徒
- Is Fox still here? - Yes, sir.
- 福克斯还在吗？ - 在
We need to send these people away.
我们要把这些客人赶走
Those are Bruce Wayne's guests. You have a name to maintain.
你不能毁了布鲁斯韦恩的名誉
I don't care about my name.
我不在乎我的名誉
It's not just your name, sir. It's your father's name.
不只是你，也是你父亲的名誉
And it's all that's left of him.
他只留下他的名誉
Don't destroy it.
千万别毁了他的名誉
- Mr. Earle. - Happy birthday, Bruce.
- 厄尔先生 - 生日快乐
Thank you.
谢谢你
How did the stock offering go?
公司的股价如何？
Prices soared.
涨停板
Who was buying?
股票都是谁在买？
All kinds of funds and brokerages.
基金和证券公司
It's a bit technical.
你不会懂的
The key thing is...
重点是
...our company's future is secure.
- 公司的未来很稳定 - 那就好
A little the worse for wear, I'm afraid.
她只是喝多了几杯
What was the plan, Crane?
你的计划是什麽？
How were you gonna get your toxin into the air?
你怎麽把毒药释放在空气中？
Scarecrow. Scarecrow.
稻草人，稻草人
Who were you working for, Crane?
替谁工作？
Oh, it's too late.
太迟了
You can't stop it now.
你阻止不了他
Here.
拿去
- Happy birthday, Bruce. - Thank you. Thanks.
- 生日快乐，布鲁斯 - 谢谢各位
And thank you for that item.
谢谢你的那样东西
You're welcome.
不客气
- I know you'll put it to good use. - I already have.
- 我知道你会用来救人 - 我已经救了一个人
How long would it take to manufacture on a large scale?
如果要大量制造要多久时间？
Weeks. Why?
几个星期，为什麽问？
Somebody's planning to disperse the toxin using the water supply.
有人想利用自来水散播毒素
The water supply won't help you disperse an inhalant.
自来水不能让人吸入毒素
What?
什麽？
Unless you have a microwave emitter powerful enough...
除非用微波发射器
...to vaporize all the water in the mains.
把水分蒸发
A microwave emitter like the one Wayne Enterprises just misplaced.
就是韦恩企业弄丢的那一台
Misplaced?
弄丢了？
Earle just fired me for asking too many questions about it.
我多问几句就被厄尔开除
Go back to Wayne Enterprises now and start making more of that antidote.
我要你回公司大量制造抗体
The police are gonna need as much as they can get their hands on.
警方会需要大量的抗体
My security clearance has been revoked.
我公司的保全卡被没收了
That wouldn't stop a man like you, would it?
你一定会有办法，对吧？
I suppose not.
我猜是吧
- Bruce, there's somebody you must meet. - Not now, Mrs. Delane.
- 布鲁斯，你一定要见一个人 - 我现在没空
Now, am I pronouncing this right...
听听我念得对不对…
...Mr. Ra's al Ghul?
忍者大师？
You're not Ra's al Ghul.
你才不是忍者大师
I watched him die.
我亲眼看到他死
But is Ra's al Ghul immortal?
也许忍者大师不会死？
Are his methods supernatural?
也许他有特异功能？
Or cheap parlor tricks to conceal your true identity, Ra's?
也许你才是真正的忍者大师吧？
Surely a man who spends his nights scrambling over the rooftops of Gotham...
你自己在晚上化身为正义使者
...wouldn't begrudge me dual identities.
应该不会怪我有双重身分吧？
I saved your life.
我救了你一命
I warned you about compassion, Bruce.
我教过你不能对敌人手下留情
Your quarrel is with me.
你要对付的是我
You let these people go.
放过这些人
You are welcome to explain the situation to them.
尽管去跟他们解释吧
Everyone.
各位
Everybody?
各位来宾请听我说
I...
我…
I want to thank you all for coming here tonight and drinking all of my booze.
要谢谢你们喝光我的酒
No, really.
我是说真的
There's a thing about being a Wayne...
像我这种亿万大富翁
...that you're never short of a few freeloaders, like yourselves...
免不了会有很多人来白吃白喝
...to fill up your mansion with. So here's to you people. Thank you.
我敬大家，谢谢各位
- That's enough, Bruce. - I'm not finished.
- 够了，布鲁斯 - 我还没说完
To all of you...
你们这些…
All of you phonies, all of you two-faced friends...
你们这些伪君子 你们这些酒肉朋友
...you sycophantic suck-ups who smile through your teeth at me...
装一副笑脸，一心想讨好我
...please, leave me in peace.
请你们别再来烦我
Please go.
请你们走吧
Stop smiling, it's not a joke. Please leave.
我不是开玩笑，快走吧
The party's over, get out.
派对结束了，快滚
The apple has fallen very far from the tree, Mr. Wayne.
你丢尽了你父母的脸，韦恩先生
Amusing.
很有意思
But pointless. None of these people have long to live.
但是没有用 这些人都活不久了
Your antics at the asylum have forced my hand.
你对疗养院的注意 逼我不得不提早行动
So Crane was working for you.
克莱恩果然是为你做事
His toxin is derived from the organic compound found in our blue flowers.
他利用蓝花提炼毒药
He was able to weaponize it.
然後做成化学武器
He's not a member of the League of Shadows?
他不是影武者联盟成员？
Of course not. He thought our plan was to hold the city to ransom.
当然不是 他以为我们要勒索高谭市
But really, you are gonna release Crane's poison on the entire city.
但是你其实要在高谭市下毒
Then watch Gotham tear itself apart through fear.
然後看着市民因为恐惧自我毁灭
You're gonna destroy millions of lives.
你打算害死数百万条人命
Only a cynical man would call what these people have "lives," Wayne.
这些人活着也是痛苦
Crime. Despair.
他们饱受犯罪荼毒
This is not how man was supposed to live.
活着还有什麽意思呢？
The League of Shadows has been a check against human corruption...
数千年来我们影武者联盟都在…
...for thousands of years.
清除人间败类
We sacked Rome. Loaded trade ships with plague rats.
我们在古罗马制造瘟疫
Burned London to the ground.
把伦敦夷为平地
Every time a civilization reaches the pinnacle of its decadence...
每当人类文明腐败到极点
...we return to restore the balance.
我们就会将它毁灭
Gotham isn't beyond saving.
高谭市还有得救
Give me more time. There are good people here.
再给我时间，这里还有好人
You're defending a city so corrupt...
这个城市无药可救了 我们渗透了每一个阶层
Time to play.
该出去玩了
When I found you in that jail, you were lost.
我在牢里看到你时，你迷失了自我
But I believed in you.
但是我相信你
I took away your fear, and I showed you a path.
我消除你的恐惧，指引你方向
You were my greatest student.
你是我最好的徒弟
It should be you standing by my side, saving the world.
你应该站在我身边拯救世界
I'll be standing where I belong.
我要站在你面前
Between you and the people of Gotham.
阻止你屠杀高谭市市民
No one can save Gotham.
没有人救得了高谭市
When a forest grows too wild, a purging fire is inevitable and natural.
当森林腐烂，野火会把它烧光
Tomorrow the world will watch in horror as its greatest city destroys itself.
明天是这座伟大城市的末日
The movement back to harmony will be unstoppable this time.
这次没有人能阻止我
- You attacked Gotham before? - Of course.
- 你曾经试过毁灭高谭市？ - 当然了
Over the ages our weapons have grown more sophisticated.
我们使用的方法越来越成熟
With Gotham we tried a new one. Economics.
我们曾经造成经济大萧条
But we underestimated certain of Gotham's citizens...
但是我们低估了像你父母这种…
...such as your parents.
善心人士的力量
Gunned down by one of the very people they were trying to help.
结果他们竟被帮助的对象打死
Create enough hunger and everyone becomes a criminal.
老百姓没饭吃被迫当强盗
Their deaths galvanized the city into saving itself...
你父母的死让高谭市民心连心
...and Gotham has limped on ever since.
勉强撑到现在
We are back to finish the job.
我们要来完成任务
And this time no misguided idealists will get in the way.
这次不会有理想主义者碍事
Like your father, you lack the courage to do all that is necessary.
你跟你爸一样狠不下心
If someone stands in the way of true justice...
如果有人敢阻止我们伸张正义
...you simply walk up behind them and stab them in the heart.
我们就从背後捅他们一刀
- I am gonna stop you. - You never did learn...
- 我要阻止你的恶行 - 你学不会…
...to mind your surroundings.
耳听四面、眼观八方
Justice is balance.
正义就是有仇必报
You burned my house and left me for dead.
你烧了我房子，差点害死我
Consider us even.
这下我们算扯平了
No one comes out. Make sure.
确定没有人活着出来
They're all gone?
他们都逃出去了？
- How many from maximum security? - Every one of them.
- 有多少重度病患逃出去？ - 全部都逃出去
Serial killers, rapists.
连环杀手、强暴犯
Raise the bridges. We don't want any getting off the island.
把桥梁升起，别让他们进城
Yeah, I'll raise the bridges...
好吧，就这麽办
...when I get every available unit out here to catch the homicidal maniacs...
等支援警力来把那些神经病抓走
...that are running loose out there. - Come on!
- 到时候再说吧 - 快去吧
I hope you're not a member of the fire brigade.
希望你不是消防队员
Master Wayne! Master Wayne!
韦恩少爷！
What is the point of all those pushups if you can't even lift a bloody log?
你成天健身连木头都抬不动？
What have I done, Alfred?
我到底做了什麽？
Everything my family...
韦恩宅邸…
...my father, built...
我父亲的心血…
The Wayne legacy is more than bricks and mortar, sir.
韦恩家族的精神不只是砖块瓦砾
I wanted to save Gotham.
我想要拯救高谭市
I failed.
我失败了
Why do we fall, sir?
我们为什麽跌倒？
So that we can learn to pick ourselves up.
这样才能学会站起来
You still haven't given up on me?
你还是没放弃我，是吗？
Never.
永远都不会
Down!
趴下来
Harassment! I see harassment!
警察暴力，警察动粗
Maybe you'd like to see some excessive force?
你想看真正的警察暴力吗？
Madman with a gun.
拿了枪的疯子
With residents furious at the unprecedented show of police strength...
市民对警方镇压行动…
...to round up the inmates... - We're about to raise these bridges.
感到愤怒
Officer, I am a Gotham City district attorney. Let me pass.
我是检察官，让我过去
- Just shut up! - Hey, Flass, cool it!
- 给我闭嘴！ - 佛莱斯，别激动！
Hold these people back.
冷静点
Hey, Gordon. Somebody here to see you.
戈登，有人来找你
- What are you doing here? - Our friend sent me with this.
- 你跑来干嘛？ - 我们的朋友要我交给你
It counteracts Crane's toxin.
这是解药
Hopefully you won't need it.
希望你用不着
Not unless he's got some way of getting that crap into the air.
除非有人把毒药释放在空气中
All right, last one across.
好了，不准过桥了
People, they want this bridge up in no more than three minutes!
三分钟内就要把桥梁升起来
Better get you off the island before they raise the bridges. Patrolman!
你最好赶快离开这里
Go!
快走吧
I can't find my mom.
我找不到我妈妈
Hey!
喂！
What the hell are you doing?
你想干什麽？
Gentlemen...
各位
...time to spread the word.
我们该行动了
And the word is...
我们要引起一阵…
...panic.
大恐慌
Jesus. The pressure, it's spiking.
水压突然上升
Right there.
就在那里
That water main is right under the Narrows.
那是奈何岛的地下水管
It's okay.
没事了
This is Commissioner Loeb.
我是罗局长
Come on, somebody talk to me.
快向我报告
Come on!
说话啊！
Loeb, Loeb. This is Gordon.
罗局长，我是戈登
What the hell is going on?
到底发生什麽事？
We need reinforcements. TAC teams, SWAT, riot cops!
我们需要支援，镇暴警察、霹雳小组
Gordon! All the city's riot police are on the island with you!
戈登，镇暴警察都在你那里
Well, they're completely incapacitated!
他们都中了毒
It's okay, it's okay. No one's gonna hurt you.
没事了，没人会伤害你
Of course they are!
我就会伤害你
- Crane? - No. Scarecrow.
- 克莱恩？ - 不，我是稻草人
Gordon...
戈登
...there's nobody left to send in.
没有警力了
So I'm on my own?
只剩下我一个人？
The Narrows is tearing itself to pieces.
奈何岛陷入一团混乱
This is just the beginning. If they hit the whole city...
如果他们将毒药释放到全市
...there's nothing to stop Gotham tearing itself apart.
就会引起高谭市的大恐慌
- How are they gonna do that? - The train.
- 他们要怎麽做？ - 透过铁路系统
The monorail follows the water mains to the central hub beneath Wayne Tower.
自来水管沿着轨道到韦恩大楼底下
If the machine gets to the station...
只要在韦恩大楼发射微波
...it'll cause a chain reaction that'll vaporize the city's water supply.
就会把全市的供水蒸发
Covering Gotham in this poison.
让高谭市充满毒气
I'm gonna stop him from loading that train, but I may need your help.
我需要你帮我阻止他们
- What do you need? - Can you drive stick?
- 你要我怎麽做？ - 你会开手排档吗？
There you are!
你们在这里
There is nothing to fear...
除了恐惧本身
...but fear itself!
没什麽好怕的
I am here to help!
我来帮你们…
Batman will save us. He'll come.
蝙蝠侠会来救我们
- He'll come. - Don't peek.
- 他一定会来 - 不要看
This is Gordon. Prepare to lower the bridge.
我是戈登，把桥放下来
I told you he'd come.
我就说他一定会来
Wait.
等等
You could die.
你很可能没命
At least tell me your name.
至少告诉我你是谁
It's not who I am underneath...
我在外表底下是谁并不重要
...but what I do that defines me.
我的所作所为才重要
Bruce?
布鲁斯？
Well, well. You took my advice about theatricality a bit literally.
你真的听我的话，扮成一个怪物
- It ends here. - For you and the police, maybe.
- 你的恶行到此为止 - 你跟警察才到此为止
My fight, however, lies with the rest of Gotham.
我要对付的是整个高谭市
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have a city to destroy.
恕我失陪，我要摧毁这座城市
- I can't beat two of your pawns? - As you wish.
- 你以为我打不过他们？ - 请便吧
GPS online.
全球定位系统连线
In 100 yards.
距离一百码
Gentlemen.
上吧
Who the hell authorized this?
谁下令把桥放下来？
Distance to Wayne Tower, three miles.
距离韦恩大楼三英哩
The pressure's moving along the mains, blowing the pipes.
水压把沿路的水管炸爆
If that pressure reaches us...
如果波及自来水厂
...the water supply right across the whole city is gonna blow!
全市的自来水管都会爆炸
At the next intersection, turn right.
在下一个街口右转
You will never learn.
你永远都学不会
Sorry.
不好意思
- Familiar. Don't you have anything new? - How about this?!
- 你没有新的招式吗？ - 这一招怎麽样？
You have arrived at Wayne Tower.
您已抵达目的地，韦恩大楼
Evacuate the building.
快疏散整座大楼
We're on top of the main hub and it's gonna blow.
楼下的自来水厂会爆炸
Weapons system activated.
启动武器系统
Nice ride.
好厉害的车
Armed.
准备攻击
Don't be afraid, Bruce.
不要怕，布鲁斯
Come on. Come on.
来吧，来吧
You are just an ordinary man in a cape.
你只是穿着披风的凡人
That's why you couldn't fight injustice, that's why you can't stop this train.
不能伸张正义，不能阻止列车
Who said anything about stopping it?
谁说我要阻止列车？
Yes!
太帅了
You never learned to mind your surroundings!
你学不会耳听四面、眼观八方
Have you finally learned to do what is necessary?
你终於学会狠下心来了？
I won't kill you...
我不会杀你
...but I don't have to save you.
但是我也不必救你
- The meeting's already started. - What meeting?
- 会议已经开始了 - 什麽会议？
Fox, I seem to remember firing you.
福克斯，我炒了你鱿鱼
You did.
没错
I got another job.
我找到新工作
Yours.
你的工作
On whose authority?
谁有这个权力？
Batman may have made the front page...
蝙蝠侠上了头版新闻
...but Bruce Wayne got pushed to page eight.
布鲁斯韦恩只上了第八版
Bruce Wayne.
我是布鲁斯韦恩
What makes you think you can decide who's running Wayne Enterprises?
你凭什麽决定谁来掌管公司？
- The fact that I'm the owner. - What are you talking about?
- 因为我是公司老板 - 你在说什麽？
The company went public a week ago.
公司一星期前上市
And I bought most of the shares.
我透过各种基金…
Through various charitable foundations and trusts and so forth.
买下大半股权
Look, it's all a bit technical, but the important thing...
你不会懂的，重点是…
...is that my company's future is secure.
我的公司的未来很稳定
Right, Mr. Fox?
对吧，福克斯先生？
Right you are, Mr. Wayne.
一点也没错
Didn't you get the memo?
你没收到通知吗？
- I'm sorry I didn't tell you, Rachel. - No. No, Bruce...
- 很抱歉我没告诉你 - 不必道歉
...I'm sorry.
不，我才要道歉
The day that Chill died, I...
齐利被枪杀那天
I said terrible things.
我对你说了重话
But true things.
那也是真话
I was a coward with a gun...
我当时是个懦夫
...and justice is about more than revenge, so thank you.
正义不代表报仇，我要谢谢你
I never stopped thinking about you.
我一直在想着你
About us.
还有我们
And when I heard you were back, I...
我听说你回来
I started to hope.
我就抱着希望
But then I found out about your mask.
但是後来我发现你的面具
Batman's just a symbol, Rachel.
蝙蝠侠只是我的化身
No. This...
不
...is your mask.
这是你的面具
Your real face is the one that criminals now fear.
现在的你是犯罪克星
The man I loved...
我深爱的人
...the man who vanished...
曾经离开我的人
...he never came back at all.
他根本就没有回来
But maybe he's still out there somewhere.
他还在世界某个角落
Maybe someday, when Gotham no longer needs Batman...
有一天高谭市不再需要蝙蝠侠
...I'll see him again.
也许我会再见到他
- Proved me wrong, you know. - About what?
- 你证明我错了 - 什麽事？
Your father would be very proud of you.
你父亲会以你为荣
Just like me.
就像我一样
What will you do?
你接下来有什麽打算？
Rebuild it.
重新开始
Just the way it was, brick for brick.
一砖一瓦重建家园
Just the way it was, sir?
就跟以前一样吗？
Yeah, why?
是啊，怎麽样？
I thought this might be a good opportunity for...
我觉得可以
...improving the foundations.
加强地基的部分
- In the southeast corner? - Precisely, sir.
- 东南角的地基吗？ - 没错
- Nice. - I couldn't find any mob bosses.
- 挺好的 - 我找不到黑帮老大绑在上面
- Well, sergeant? - It's "lieutenant" now.
- 警官 - 我现在是队长了
You really started something.
你改变了现状
Bent cops running scared.
坏警察不敢再乱来
Hope on the streets.
人们也充满希望
- But? - The Narrows is lost.
- 但是呢？ - 奈何岛仍然被罪犯控制
And we still haven't picked up Crane or half the inmates of Arkham that he freed.
克莱恩和变态恶徒也没落网
We will.
我们会抓到他们的
We can bring Gotham back.
我们可以拯救高谭市
- What about escalation? - Escalation?
- 道高一尺、魔高一丈？ - 怎麽说？
We start carrying semiautomatics, they buy automatics.
警察开始用半自动步枪 歹徒就买自动步枪
We start wearing Kevlar, they buy armor-piercing rounds.
我们穿防弹衣，他们用达姆弹
- And? - And you're wearing a mask...
- 然後呢？ - 你戴着面具
...and jumping off rooftops.
飞檐走壁
Now, take this guy.
就拿这家伙来说
Armed robbery, double homicide.
杀人放火、无恶不作
Got a taste for the theatrical, like you.
他跟你一样爱玩变装秀
Leaves a calling card.
犯案後都留下名片
I'll look into it.
我会查查他的底细
I never said thank you.
我一直没谢谢你
And you'll never have to.
你也永远不用谢我